men thank you brother Elko for uh coming
back despite the technical difficulty
um thank you for the prayers
um
and we are we are ready to get into the
word of God uh today please put a one in
the chat
if you are ready for the word of God
um we're going to be doing an in-depth
study uh today on the subject of the
gift of tongues
the gift of tongues
and as you know there is a lot of
confusion regarding this subject
um what exactly is the gift of tongues
we're going to be looking at that today
we're going to be going on a journey
through the scriptures
I'm going to be seeing what the word of
God has to say on this subject and what
is actually lacking in the word of God
on this subject
so with that said let's go ahead and
pray we're going to jump right in
um let's pray I hope you are taking
notes
um please share this link with people
that you believe may need to hear this
message and uh let's get into this let's
pray Heavenly Father
we ask Lord for your blessing as we open
your word please Lord speak to us
uh show us truth Lord this is our prayer
in Jesus name we ask it amen amen so
once again
what is the biblical gift of tongues
we're going to go to the screen
we're gonna go to the screen and um we
are going to uh begin
with the book of Acts
chapter 2 beginning with verse 1 and the
Bible says
and when the day of Pentecost was fully
come they were all with one Accord
in one place I want you to put that in a
chat for me one Accord in one place one
Accord in one place the Bible says and
suddenly there came a sound from Heaven
as of a rushing Mighty Wind and it
filled all the house where they were
sitting
and they were paired unto them and they
were appeared unto them clothing tongues
like as a fire and it sat upon each of
them and this is where we find uh the
gift of tongues first introduced it is
on the day of Pentecost the disciples
are gathered together in one place and
they are praying to God the Bible says
they prayed for 10 days and at the end
of that period of Prayer
uh the holy spirit is poured out and the
disciples receive the gift of tongues
the gift of tongues now this is a gift
that is first introduced in the New
Testament but we want to know why was
this gift introduced
why was this gift introduced that's a
very important question if we don't know
the reason that this gift was introduced
then it is very likely that we're going
to misunderstand the purpose of this
gift
so
in order to understand why this gift was
introduced we're going to go back to the
beginning we're going to go to the Book
of Genesis
and we're going to go to Genesis chapter
11 beginning with verse 1.
Genesis 11 and verse 1 the Bible says
and the whole Earth
was of one language
and of one speech now let's pause for a
second let's come back uh come back to
the screen
so the Bible tells us here in Genesis 11
we don't you know we're not sure what
we're going to read on yet
what what where what what we're going to
see we're just looking at Genesis 11
verse 1 where it says that at this time
whatever time this was the whole world
was of one speech
one language we might say one tongue
because the word tongue actually means
language so the whole world was of one
tongue let's go back to the screen verse
two
Genesis 11 and verse 2. the Bible says
here and it came to pass as they
journeyed from the East that they found
a plane in the land of Sinar and they
dwelt there and they said one to another
go to let us make brick
put that word in the chat for me please
I need y'all to to to focus on certain
things so when I say put that word in
the chat or Mark that word I need you to
mark that word let us make brick and
burn them through Lee
and they had breakfast Stone
brick for stone put that word in the
chat for me please Stone
they had breakfast Stone and slime had
they for Mortar
and they said go to let us build us a
city and a tower put those words in the
chat for me please a city and a tower
whose top May reach onto heaven and let
us make us a name
lest we be scattered abroad upon the
face of the whole earth now remember the
flood had just occurred in Genesis
chapter 6 7 and 8. so here in Genesis 11
they're trying to find a way to to avoid
another catastrophe and they're trying
to build a tower that's going to reach
unto heaven so the Bible says
the Bible says in verse 5.
and the Lord came down
to see the city and the tower which the
children of men building
and the Lord God said behold the people
is one and they have all one language
and this they begin to do and now
nothing will be restrained from them
which they have imagined to do
go go to let us go down and there do
what
confound their language that they may
not understand
one another's speech
so we see here that that uh uh the world
was of one language one tongue and they
conspire together to to actually as it
were if it were even possible to try to
get into heaven we're gonna build a city
that reaches unto heaven
God says this is what they do we're
going to go down and we're going to
confound or confuse
their language
and this is the origin of multiple
tongues
multiple languages
notice what the text goes on to say in
verse 8.
so the Lord
scattered them abroad upon the face of
the Earth and they left off to build the
city therefore
is the name of it called dabble because
the Lord did there confound the language
of all the Earth and from thence to the
Lord scattered them abroad upon the face
of all the Earth all right
so we should be all be on the same page
thus far this is where multiple
languages are introduced because men
were all on one Accord and in one place
deciding to find a way to get to heaven
a way that was not ordained of God but
they wanted to find a way to get to
heaven of their own works of their own
will of their own accord
and what God does is he comes down and
he confounds their languages now as a
result of this the the the the the world
is divided by language
we go back to the screen we'll see in
Genesis chapter 10 verse 5 the Bible
says by these were the Isles of the
Gentiles by these were the Isles of the
Gentiles divided
divided in their lands everyone after
his tongue after their families in their
Nations again Genesis chapter 10 31.
these are the sons of Shem after their
families after their tongues in their
lands after their Nation so what I want
you to know is this
After the flood Noah has three sons sham
or Shem japheth and ham and they are
divided by languages this is After the
flood occurs in Genesis chapter 11. they
are divided by languages so the lineage
through which the promised seed was to
come that is Jesus was through the
lineage of Shem and when we're talking
about the lineage of Shem we're talking
specifically about the Hebrew people
now what does this tell us
out of all the tongues in the world God
was only going to deal with one what
put it in the chat for me he was only
going to communicate with one
tongue
with one
tongue with one
people
what tongue was that
y'all can help me out he already gave
the answer the tongue was the Hebrew
tongue or the Hebrew people
so please note that God was not going to
communicate with other nations he had
chosen a very specific Nation or a very
specific tongue
the Bible says in Exodus chapter 20
verse 19 God leads the children of
Israel we go through through some
history the children of Israel go into
captivity in Egypt God sends Moses to
deliver them and then Moses leads them
to Mount Sinai and we read these words
and they said unto Moses speak thou with
us and we will hear but let not God
speak with us lest we die and Moses said
unto the people fear not for God has
come to prove you that his fear may be
before your faces
and the people stood afar off and Moses
Drew near unto the thick Darkness where
God was and so what we see here
is that God
draws near and interacts with the Hebrew
people meaning the Hebrew tongue
he's going to be speaking and and and
and and and and and communicating
with one specific people
in fact in Deuteronomy Deuteronomy
chapter 4 verse 32.
the Bible says for ask now of the days
that are passed which were before thee
since the day that God created man upon
the Earth and asked from the one side of
Heaven unto the other unto the other
where there has been any such thing as
this great thing is or has been heard
like it did ever people hear the voice
of God speaking out of the midst of the
fire as thou has heard it and live
or
has God aside to go and take him a
nation from the midst of another Nation
by temptations by Signs by wonders and
by War and by Mighty hand and by
stretched out arms and by great Terrors
according to all that the Lord your God
did for you in Egypt before your eyes so
all we're simply seeing here is that God
was calling one nation one tongue and he
was going to speak through that one
nation that one tongue
now we need to understand that God can
speak in any tongue God can speak in any
language God can speak in every language
but he was only going to speak to one
people and that was the Hebrew people
now what were these people why is God
dealing with the Hebrew Nation what is
he calling them for I want you to know
with me in Exodus chapter 19
and verse 5. where the Bible says now
therefore if you'll obey my voice and
keep my Covenant then you shall be a
peculiar treasure unto me above all
people for all the Earth is mine and you
shall be unto me a kingdom of priests
and a holy nation these are the words
which thou shall speak unto the children
of Israel so God was calling Israel the
Hebrew people the Hebrew tongue to be a
holy and peculiar Nation
I hope you're following me here we're
just building a foundation that is going
to help help us to understand why God
gives the gifts of tongues
in the book of Acts
now not only did God call the children
of Israel to be a peculiar Nation or
people but he also called them to do
something very interesting in Exodus 25
and verse 8 the Bible says this God
speaking says let them make me a
sanctuary that I may dwell among them
now because let's let's
I want you to watch this and watch this
carefully
the sanctuary was the house of God
God said I want you to build me a tower
I'm sorry
build me a sanctuary
because through this sanctuary I'm going
to show you the Bible says in Psalm 77
13 thy way o God is in the sanctuary so
the house of God the sanctuary was
designed to show man to show the Hebrews
how to get where
come on y'all put it in the chat for me
foreign
how to get
to heaven
now remember
in Genesis chapter 11
mankind says we're going to get to
heaven and we're gonna we're gonna build
a way to get to heaven we're going to
create our own path to Heaven we're
going to build our own tower that we
feel will get us to heaven
God says no no no no no no that's not
the way this works that's not how you
get to heaven and he confounds their
languages then he chooses one language
one people the Hebrew language the
Hebrew people the Hebrew tongue and he
says now you people I want you to make
me a sanctuary that I may dwell among
you make me a sanctuary that I may show
you the way to heaven
now why is God doing this why is God
showing the Hebrews the way to heaven is
it so that the Hebrews can be saved
is it that God just wanted one people to
get to know how to get to heaven no no
no no let's go back to the screen and
we're going to see according to the Book
of Micah chapter 4 verse 2 this was the
plan
and many nations shall come and say come
and let us go up to the mountain of the
Lord and to the house of the god of
Jacob and he will teach us his ways and
we will walk in his paths for the law
shall go forth of Zion and the word of
Lord from Jerusalem all right
y'all catch this
watch this now listen to me carefully
guys
All Nations
give me another word for that all
nations when I say all nations what do I
mean by that
where did the nation start
where did the different nationalities
begin they began at the Tower of Babel
where God confounded the language so now
in Michael 4 2 God is saying listen my
goal is to bring all these tongues yes
Lisa
um
my goal is to bring all these tongues to
Israel to Jerusalem because there
there is where the true way to heaven
will be found I'm gonna use you Israel
I'm going to use you Hebrew Israel I'm
going to use you I'm going to speak to
you
to prepare you
to help save the world
so I'm only dealing with your tongue now
but the goal is all tongues all people
are gonna come and see that Glory that
that salvation will be found in
Jerusalem
and we understand that that salvation
was was pointing forward to Jesus Christ
are y'all with me so far
so so note again in with me in first
Chronicles chapter 16 verse 24 this was
always the goal listen carefully declare
his glory
among the heathen
His Marvelous Works among all nations
now do y'all see a problem here
do y'all see a problem here
because if you're a Hebrew if you're a
Hebrew
you only speak
do you catch with her if you're a Hebrew
you most likely only speak Hebrew so God
pray tell how how are you going to help
us
to bring
all these other tongues
all these other nations all these other
languages how are you gonna because
there's a barrier remember what you did
back in Genesis chapter 11 there's a
barrier they can't understand us we
can't understand them so God says my uh
uh uh Abraham the the descendants of
Abraham I'm going to use you
I'm going to speak to you
to show you the proper thing that gets
people to Heaven it's not the tower it's
the sanctuary it's the temple it's the
Plan of Salvation so I'm going to help
have you build that and and if you are
faithful the nations are going to come
to you
now if you're not faithful
if you're not faithful I want you to
notice what the Bible says what God told
them listen if you're not faithful in
what I say watch this Deuteronomy 28
Deuteronomy 28 verse 48 the Bible says
this therefore
if you're not faithful God said
you will serve your enemies which the
Lord shall send against thee in a hunger
and in thirst and in nakedness and in
want of all things and he shall put a
yoke of iron upon thy neck until he have
destroyed thee watch this the Lord shall
bring a nation against thee from far
from the ends of the Earth as Swift as
the eagle flyeth a nation who's what
a nation whose tongue thou shall not
understand
now we know that God is here for telling
of the nation Babylon
how interesting Babel
Babel
Babylon
the Tower of Babel where God confounded
the language and then he calls the
Israelites he calls a Adam or Abraham
I'm sorry and he calls the Hebrew people
and he says I'm calling you for Mission
your mission is to reach the entire
world every nation in tongue however if
you disobey me I am going to send you to
a nation whose tongue you don't
understand and what nation would it
happen to be Babylon
thank you
babble
on
know what the text says Jeremiah chapter
5 15 again God speaking load I will
bring a nation upon you from afar o
House of Israel save the Lord it is a
mighty nation it is an ancient Nation a
nation whose language thou knowest not
neither understand this what they say
again in Isaiah 28 11
forward stammering lips and another
tongue
will he speak to this people the context
of Isaiah 28 is is God speaking to the
children of Israel saying because y'all
are so hard of hearing because you will
not listen to me I am going to punish
you and I'm going to speak to you
through a people of another tongue
people who are Gentiles people who are
not of the Hebrew tongue I'm going to
send you into a foreign land
and I'm going to speak to you with the
people of another tongue so what I want
you to see here clearly is that another
tongue here is it signifies another
language that is understood by people
but it is an unknown language in that it
is not understood by those who don't
speak that particular language
the Babylonians did not speak in an
unknown tongue it was an unknown tongue
to the Israelites for the one in the
chat if you follow so far
it was an unknown tongue to the
Israelites but it wasn't an unknown
tongue to everybody on the planet
it was an unknown tongue to those who
didn't understand the language
so
we know what happens
we know that that that that that Israel
refused to obey God and they end up
going into Babylonian captivity
now it is while they are there in
Babylonian captivity and and I'm just
gonna go ahead I'm not I had these
slides out to read but I'm not gonna I'm
not gonna read these
because I want to save some time here
it is in the Book of Daniel
chapter 9 where Daniel is praying for
forgiveness of the sins of Israel
and and in that prayer in Daniel 9 while
he's praying the angel Gabriel appears
to him and says listen the Lord has
heard your prayer and I'm about to
explain something to you and it is here
where this prop this time prophecy is
given called the 70 week prophecy and in
this prophecy God is basically laying
out that if you start from a certain
time Daniel from the from the time a
certain thing happens you count 70 weeks
it's going to bring you to the Messiah
and what God is saying to Israel in this
prophecy is look
y'all rebelled against me and now you're
in Babylonian captivity I'm about to
forgive you
in fact this 70-week prophecy is
significant for the very fact that 70
weeks is 70 times 7 and you'll remember
let's just go to the screen very quickly
you'll remember what the Bible says in
Matthew 18 22 when Peter is asking Jesus
how often shall my enemies sin against
me and I forgive him till seven times
Jesus said I say not unto thee until
seven times but until 70 times 7 70
times 7 beloved is the number of
forgiveness
so in this prophecy God is saying listen
to Israel I'm going to forgive you for
not doing for not fulfilling the mission
I've called you to fulfill now I'm about
to send the Messiah I'm about to send my
son
when he comes if you reject him at the
end of this 70 times 7 period if you
reject him
the punishment that I delayed because
I'm forgiving you is going to be meted
out upon you
in fact if you look at the last part of
this prophecy in Daniel chapter 9 note
with me Daniel chapter 9 verse 26 notice
what the Bible says
Daniel 9 20 26 the Bible says uh no
therefore and understand that from the
going forth of the Commandment to
restore and to build Jerusalem unto the
Messiah the prince shall be seven weeks
and he goes on to list the time and then
notice with me after three scoring two
weeks some the Messiah be cut off that
means crucified Israel was going to
reject the Messiah now watch this
and the people of the prince that shall
come shall destroy the city
and the sanctuary
now let's come back to the screen for a
moment
I need you to remember this what was the
purpose of the city and the sanctuary
remember in Genesis 11 what are they
trying to build a tower and a city that
reaches onto Heaven God says no no no no
no you don't determine how you get to
heaven you can't determine how you get
to heaven what needs I'm I'm gonna come
down I'm going to confound your
languages
and now I'm going to choose the Hebrew
nation and I'm going to show them this
is how you so we're going to build a
city and a sanctuary I'm going to
instruct you the right way to get to
heaven this Sanctuary this is the path
to Heaven this city Jerusalem this is
where I'm gonna send my son that is
going to show you the way to heaven so
what is what does Israel do they begin
to rebel against God and they end up in
Babylonian captivity now God says I'm
gonna forgive you but I'm giving you
another chance but if at the end of this
70 times seven
you don't obey you don't accept the the
path I have laid out for heaven
then something is going to happen
so this 70-week prophecy brings us right
up to the New Testament it brings us to
the time of Christ it brings us to the
death of Christ just as the prophecy
said and guess what happens in the very
year of the crucifixion of Christ can
anyone tell me what happened
50 days
after Jesus is crucified
what happens 50 days I'm sorry after
Jesus is resurrected what happens 50
days after this
it is God
literally telling his people
remember the promise that I was giving
you that all nations are going to come
to you that that I'm going to use you to
reach all nations if you will accept the
sacrifice if you will accept my son who
died for you yes y'all Pentecost on the
day come on let's
listen to this y'all come with me to the
screen I all need to see this
y'all need to see this on the day of
Pentecost the Bible says there were
dwelling at Jerusalem Jews devout men
out of every nation under heaven
now when this was noised abroad the
multitude came together and were
confounded because that every man heard
them speak in his own language
and they were all amazed and marveled
saying one to another behold are not all
these would speak Galilean meaning they
only got one tongue how here we every
man in our own tongue wherein we were
born I need y'all to catch this
in Genesis
chapter 11.
all nations were one they were all
gathered together in one place
but they were gathered together to find
a way to heaven that was not ordained of
God
and so God confounds their languages
when y'all get together and y'all want
to try I'm gonna confound your languages
I'm going to choose a nation one tongue
and I'm gonna minister to that one
tongue to show them the true way to
heaven I'm gonna help them build and
show them this is how you get to heaven
and then I'm gonna use them to bring
this message to all these other nations
why because God so loved not the Hebrews
God so loved the world the world every
nation Kindred tongue and people that he
sent his only begotten son so now his
son has been sacrificed and in the very
year according to the prophecy that his
son of sacrifice God says now I'm going
to equip you Israel
remember these men are coming from Every
Other Nation they are all in Jerusalem
for a special feast and God says I'm
gonna pour out the spirit on you so that
now you can take this message
back to Every Nation Kindred tongue and
people
those who did not have access to this
because of the language barrier on the
day of Pentecost the language barrier is
broken down
now why have I used this why have I
built this up like this because there is
one verse I need you to understand
it is found in First Corinthians chapter
14 which is the tongues chapter yes
we're going to get to the tongues
chapter but I need you to understand
this because right in the middle of the
tongues chapter Paul writes this listen
to me watch this first Corinthians 14
verse 21.
in the law it is written
so Paul is talking about the gift of
tongues and now he's about to tell us
the origin the root text
for tongues
in the law it is written he says with
men
of other tongues
another lips
will I speak unto these people
and yet
for all that they will not hear me say
the Lord
listen to me all
Paul is literally quoting those verses
we read I will speak unto this people
with stammering lips and lips of another
Nation he's literally quoting this as
the basis for the gift of tongues
you see Not only was God Listen to Me
Not only was God saying to Israel as he
poured out this Spirit on the day of
Pentecost Not only was he saying I am
equipping you to go take the gospel to
the world if you will accept it if you
will accept the Messiah if you will
understand that this is me at work
not only is God doing that but what he's
also doing is he's saying listen if
y'all are not going to take this message
I am going to equip people from Every
Other Nation to do it themselves
foreign
in the chat
if you understand
what's going on please put a one in the
chat if you understand there is a reason
God pours out the spirit on the day of
Pentecost and on this day of Pentecost
the Bible says Peter gets up to preach
now watches the disciples are speaking
in all these different what
what are they speaking everyone
different
human languages
let me let me let's go back to the
screen because y'all need to see this
let's go back to the screen
with angels of other tongues and other
lips will I speak unto this people
is that what the text says
with angels
with what
with men of other tongues men of other
languages meaning come back to the
screen with me meaning we are talking
about here human languages
Paul is literally telling us God is
going to pour out this Supernatural gift
where the receiver will be able to speak
other let human languages that he was
not able to speak before
and the book of Acts 2 literally tells
us that hey how are we hearing everybody
in our own languages they're speaking
our language
coming back to the screen
I want you to see this in Matthew 21
Matthew 21 Jesus says this hear another
parable
there was a certain household in which
planted a Vineyard and hedged it about
and dig the wine press and built a tower
build a tower build a tower
built a tower put that word in a chat
for me please Jesus is giving a parable
and he's saying there's a certain
householder meaning God who has planted
a Vineyard and heads it round about and
dig the wine press and build a tower
what is the purpose of a tower y'all
come on
what were they trying to build back in
Genesis chapter 11. they were trying to
build a tower
the this Parable God is saying I'm
making a tower and he and and and and he
led it out to the husband then and went
into a far country and when the time
Drew near for the fruit he sent his
servants to the husband then that they
might receive the fruit thereof and the
husband then took his servants and beat
one and killed another and stoned
another again he sent out other servants
more than the first and they did unto
them likewise but last of all he said
unto them I will send my son they will
reverence my son
but when the husband and saw the sun
they said among themselves this is the
air come let us kill him and let us
seize upon his inheritance and they
caught him and cast him out of the
vineyard and slew him when the Lord
therefore of that Vineyard cometh what
will he do unto the husband then they
say unto him he will miserably destroy
those wicked men and let out his
Vineyard unto other husbandmen which
shall render him the fruits in their
season Jesus saith unto them watch this
Jesus saved unto them did you never read
in the scriptures the stone which the
build is rejected the stone the stone
the stone let us take Brick we're gonna
build something with bricks with stones
the stone that the Builder rejected the
same is become the head of the corner
this is the Lord's doing and it is
marvelous in our eyes therefore say unto
you the kingdom of God shall be taken
from you and given to a nation a nation
bringing forth the fruits thereof now
they each other understand this when God
is saying I'm gonna bring another Nation
what he's saying is I'm going to raise
up another tongue another people are
y'all following this
I'm going to raise up another people
that are going to do what you were
supposed to do
but in order for them to do that in
order for them to take the message that
you were supposed to take into the world
in order for them to do that I've got to
bless my people with this gift I've got
to bless my faithful Hebrews the
disciples that 120 with this gift that
they can take this message
are y'all following me
there is a reason behind this gift and
and so it is so interesting because know
what Jesus said in Matthew chapter 24
verse 2 know what Jesus said here he
said unto them see ye not all these
things verily out saying to you there
shall not be left one stone one brick
one brick
upon another that shall not be thrown
down so come back come back with me
remember this
remember in Genesis 11 they sought to
build a tower they sought to build this
thing that would lead them into heaven
and what happens God comes down because
of their rebellion and the bricks and
stones are that he stops the work
what happens when they reject Jesus in
the Gospels
he says this Temple
these stones
the work I called you to do
I'm about to throw it down
there will not be left one stone upon
another why because
the word god called you to do the
mission I called you to
you refuse
and so now God takes a people out of the
Hebrews he takes those faithful people
who accept him and he says now I'm going
to give you the gift of tongues and you
are going to go and take this message
into all the world and now you can begin
to understand why God pours out the gift
of tongues because you see he is tasking
the early church with a mission remember
let's go back to the screen Genesis
chapter 11 verse 3 they said one to
another go to let us make brick
and burn them thoroughly and they had
brick for what put the word in the chat
for me they had break four stone and
slime that is the thing that would hold
it together they had for Mortar
and they said go to let us build us a
city and a tower whose top May reach
unto heaven and let us make us a name
lest we be scattered abroad upon the
face of the whole earth and the Lord
came down to see the city and the tower
which the children of men build it so
remember the Lord comes down as they're
building hmm
what is God doing on the day of
Pentecost
he's beginning a new work
he's doing a new thing
you say what is that new thing
he's building a new city
you see beloved Malachi Matthew chapter
five
Matthew Chapter 5 and verse 14.
the Bible speaking of the church says
you are the light of the world
a city
that is set on a hill
cannot be hidden
a city that is set on the hill cannot be
hid I need you to understand that in the
New Testament times in the New Testament
dispensation a city is being built
and this city is designed to reach unto
heaven
to show people how to get to heaven
are y'all following me again Hebrews
chapter 12 verse 2 Hebrews chapter 12
verse 2 but you won't come unto Mount
Zion and unto the city of the Living God
the heavenly Jerusalem and to an
innumerable company of angels is that up
on the screen do you see that
all right I think my screen
may have just gone away
can you see this on the screen
there we go there we go
um
there it is
Hebrews 12 22 but you are coming to
Mount Zion and to the city of the Living
God the heavenly Jerusalem to an
innumerable company of angels this city
beloved this city that is symbolic of
the church
symbolizes the path to Heaven that's
what God is building today in fact in
Luke Chapter 14 verse 26 the Bible says
if any man come after me I'll come to me
and and not hate father and mother wife
children and Brethren and sisters he or
his own life he cannot be my disciple
and whosoever does not bear his cross
and come after me cannot be my disciple
and then notice what he says next for
which of you intending to build a tower
intending to build a tower let me say it
once more intending to build a tower
y'all
listen
that tower that is being built
is the tower that leads to the y'all are
catching it now oh the Flies are
changing on every slide you get it now
you understand now God beloved is
interested in every nation Kindred
tongue and people and the reason he gave
the gift of tongues was to demonstrate
that the gospel is for everybody
this is why the Bible says in Psalm 1810
Psalm 1810 the name of the Lord is a
strong tower the righteous runeth into
it and is safe it is a tower
yes we are building a tower to heaven we
are building a city to heaven but that
Tower beloved is the Lord Jesus Christ
that City beloved is the church
and check this out what are the stones
what are the stones notice with me First
Peter chapter 2 verse 4 to whom coming
as unto a living Stone
disallowed indeed of men but chosen of
God and precious ye also as Lively
stones are built up a spiritual house a
holy priesthood to offer up spiritual
sacrifices acceptable to God by Jesus
Christ and Ephesians chapter 1 3 says
this blessed be the God and father of
our Lord Jesus Christ who has blessed us
with spiritual blessings in Heavenly
places in Christ
you see beloved this city this city
called the church and this Tower which
is Christ and these Stones which
represent the people God says I'm now
going to give you the gift of tongues so
you can go out into the world and gather
Jamaican stones
Mexican stones
Italian stones
y'all get the idea every stone stones
from every nation
to build
this city
that will ultimately Lift us up into
Heavenly places and again this is why
Ephesians chapter 2 6 says this that he
has raised us up together and made us
sit together in Heavenly places in
Christ Jesus that in the ages to come he
might show the exceeding Riches of his
grace and his kindness toward us through
Christ Jesus for by grace are you saved
through faith and none of yourselves it
is a gift of God not of words says any
man should boast for we are his
workmanship created in Christ Jesus unto
good works which God has before ordained
that we should walk in them so that's
the stone beloved we are the stones what
about the mortar what's that glue that
holds us together let me just let me
just show you let me just show you I'm
gonna go right to Ephesians chapter two
and I need you to see this Ephesians
chapter 2 and verse 9 or verse verse 22.
let me go back to verse 21 verse 21. it
says now therefore you are no more
strangers and foreigners but fellow
citizens with the Saints and the
household of God and you are built upon
the foundation of the Apostles and
Prophets Jesus Christ himself being the
Chief Cornerstone watch this in home all
fitly or in whom all the building
hit the frame together
growth into a holy Temple in the Lord in
whom you are also building together for
an habitation of God through the spirit
it is the spirit that is the mortar it
is the spirit that draws everyone
together and beloved when the Holy
Spirit poured out was poured out through
the gift of tongues upon the people that
is the thing that started bringing the
bricks together what I want you to
understand beloved is that this is a
language that people were given the gift
to speak
for the sole purpose of gathering stones
to build
to build the city of God
y'all want to see some powerful look
Genesis 11 8 so the Lord scattered them
abroad from thence upon the face of the
Earth and they left off to build the
city that's what happened in Genesis 11.
you know what happens in the book of
Acts therefore they that were scattered
abroad went everywhere preaching the
word now y'all need to
oh
y'all need to see this
in Genesis 11
they are scattered abroad because their
tongues are confounded they can't
understand each other and so they leave
off building the city
in Acts chapter 8 they are scattered
abroad they are being persecuted but
they are scattered abroad with the gift
of tongues in order to preach the word
everywhere
everywhere why because according to John
chapter 11 52 here's what the Bible says
and not for the nation only not for the
nation only but that but that also he
should gather together in one the
children of God that were scattered
abroad Ephesians chapter 1 verse 10 that
in the dispensation of the fullness of
times he might gather together in one
all things in Christ both which are in
heaven and which are on earth even in
him and beloved let me you need to
follow this and Acts chapter 2 verse 11.
they said we do hear them speak in our
tongues the wonderful works of God what
were they speaking on the day of
Pentecost what was the work of god
notice John 6 28 then said they unto him
what shall we do that mean we might work
the works of God he answered and said
this is the work of God that you believe
on him whom he has sent do y'all
understand this
gee on the day of Pentecost the
disciples are not speaking in some
mysterious language that no one knows
they are speaking the mystery of God the
work of God meaning Jesus Christ on the
cross they are lifting up Christ on the
cross people are understanding what they
are saying
and accepting Christ as a result from
every nation Kindred trunk and people
and beloved now you can see the
importance of Revelation chapter 14 6
which has always been the mission of God
listen to what it says
and I saw another angel fly in the midst
of Heaven having the Everlasting gospel
to preach unto them that dwell on the
earth and to Every Nation Kindred and
tongue and people
same with a loud voice fear God and give
glory to him for the hour of his
judgment has come and worship him that
made Heaven the Earth and all The
Fountains of waters all right
come on y'all
we're about to we're about to get to the
Crux of the message now
because what I want you to understand is
some people are saying okay pastor we
get it
there is a gift
there is a gift that
clearly points to the disciples ability
to to speak in other languages
but what about
the Heavenly language
okay
sometimes what y'all are thinking right
come come I want you to show I want to
show you Satan's counterfeit here okay
y'all need to see this in Genesis
chapter 11 verse 7. Genesis chapter 11
verse 7 remember what God Said go to let
us go down and there confound their
language
that they may not understand
one another's speech
that they may not understand one
another's speech now when God did this
he was doing this in order to prevent
the work of them building the city right
building a false City
let me ask you
do you think Satan might want to do the
same thing to stop the building
of God City
what do you think
do you think Satan would want to
confound
in other words how can I counter this
outpouring of languages can I in some
way or another make it so that this gift
is seen as something else other than
what it actually is
come follow me First Corinthians 13
verse one we're going to deal with this
first and then we're going to close off
with First Corinthians chapter 14. we're
going to go through we're going to we're
going to break this chapter down first
Corinthians 13. Paul writes here though
I speak with the tongue of men
and of angels and I have not charity I
am become as sounding brass or a
tinkling symbol now let me just break
this down very quickly because a lot of
people believe that there is there is a
thing called tongues of angels here's a
problem with that
every time you see an angel speak in the
Bible every time every time you hear a
prophet listening to an angel speak in
the Bible or overhearing Angels speak in
the Bible the prophet never says can
someone translate that for me because I
don't understand what the angel just
said I don't speak this Angel's language
we have no instance in the entire Bible
not a single verse
in which
angels
are speaking
and the people and and the prophets
don't understand it
God speaks when God speaks to man he's
speaking to man
he's speaking to Angels I mean he's
speaking to me angels are speaking to
man and there is no there is no like
okay if I speak to you in this language
then you'll better understand it no no
no no if an angel says to Daniel an
angel says to Jeremiah or an angel says
to Joshua whatever they said there was
no need for someone to to go okay well
all angels and and
okay
when Paul here was speaking
he's using what is called hyperbolic
language
in other words he's saying look though I
give my body to be burned and have not
love I'm nothing though I could speak as
perfectly although I could speak with
tongues of men and of angels he's saying
though my language were as perfect as if
I was an angel and have not love
I
am as nothing
what I need you to understand below
is that
there is no special language
where God says okay I can communicate
better with you through this language
and by the way if Satan overhears this
then we're really in trouble
because that's kind of the concept but
you got to ask yourself wait a minute
how was how was how was uh Joseph
praying to G to God and how was was how
were the prophets talking to God in the
Old Testament could the devil over here
and suddenly have power over them
because no no guys
the devil has no power
to disrupt your prayer
you can pray out loud you can pray
silent you don't need a special language
and again there is no instance
let me go to First Corinthians 14. I'm
going to show you something
First Corinthians chapter 14. let's go
to First Corinthians chapter 14 and this
is where people really get confused so
we're gonna go First Corinthians 14.
we're gonna close out with this first
Corinthians Chapter 14 verse one follow
after charity and desire spiritual gifts
but rather that you may prophesy for he
that speaketh in an unknown tongue now
by the way the word unknown here is
italicize if you have a King James Bible
you'll see it is italicized meaning the
word unknown is not in this entire
chapter
so when people read an unknown tongue
they're thinking an unknown tongue to
everybody what the text is actually
saying is a tongue that you don't
understand because you don't speak that
language
French would be an unknown tongue to me
because I don't understand it
so when Paul is writing here Paul's
complain and by the way First
Corinthians 14 is a complaint
Paul is making a complaint about the way
that the church in Corinth is using this
gift of tongues so he says here for he
that speaketh in an unknown tongue
speaketh not unto men but unto God
listen to this for no man understands
him
in other words
if I'm in the church
and I'm speaking
French
and nobody there is from France
whatever I'm saying is not benefiting
the congregation because y'all know what
I'm saying God understands my speech
but you all don't understand because
you're not you don't speak French or
Italian or whatever the language might
be this is Paul's whole argument
so he's saying God understands you but
nobody else understands you now people
read this and they go oh so see there's
a language that men don't understand
that only Gods understand only God
understands no that's not what the text
is saying Paul is arguing with the corn
Church he's saying why are you speaking
why are you using your gift when you
don't need to use your gift
why are you using this gift in a in a
church in which no one speaks that
language what are you are you showing
off
what are you doing come on let's go back
to the text it says for he that speaketh
in an unknown tongue speaketh not unto
men but unto God for no man nobody
understands him why he's speaking in the
spirit that is under the gift of tongues
he's speaking the Mysteries he's
speaking the gospel that's what the
Mysteries are it's not a mysterious
language it's not a mysterious tongue
he's speaking the mysteries of the
gospel and he's show boning in a
language that nobody understands because
nobody there speaks that language how do
we know Paul's saying this let's keep
reading let's keep reading
he that prophesied speak of Unto men to
edification and exaltation and comfort
he that speaketh in an unknown tongue
edifies himself
but he that prophesied edifies the
church why I would rather ye I would
that you all speak with tongues but
rather than that you prophesy for
greater is he that prophesies than he
that speaketh with tongues except there
and except he interprets that the church
may receive edifying come back with me
for a moment
do y'all understand what Paul is saying
here
why are you speaking
Dutch
when no one here understands Dutch
if you're going to use your tongue
translate it so that people can be
edified
if you're going to speak this tongue
translate it so that others can edify
others can be edified that's what Paul
is saying here that's what his argument
is with the church in Corinth come back
to the screen and let's keep reading
notice what he goes on to say
he says now Brethren if I come to you
speaking with tongues what shall I
profit you except I shall speak to you
either by Revelation or by knowledge or
by prophesy or by Doctrine what use is
it he's saying and even things without
life give sound whether pipe or harp
except they give an extinct a distinct
distinction in the sounds how should it
be known what is piped our heart for if
the Trump is given uncertain sound who
shall prepare himself to battle
so likewise you accept you utter by the
Tongue words easy to be understood how
shall it be known what is spoken for you
shall speak into the air
now beloved I need you to understand
here Paul is not talking about some
unknown language that no one knows
Paul is talking about why are you
speaking German an example why are you
speaking German when no one around you
is going to be benefited by it your Ed
you're you're edifying yourself you
understand what you're saying but nobody
else understands what you're saying
come on keep going come back to the
screen notice what it says
there are it may be so many kinds of
voices in the world and none of them is
without significance without
significance therefore if I know not the
meaning of the voice I shall be unto him
that speaketh a barbarian and he that
speaketh shall be a barbarian unto me
now is that what God wants in a church
people thinking that we're barbarians
absolutely not Paul is trying to say
here please use common sense even so you
if for as much as you are zealous of
spiritual gifts seek that ye may excel
to edify another church wherefore let
him that speak even an unknown tongue
that is a language that others don't
understand pray that he may interpret
for if I pray in an unknown tongue my
spirit prays but my understanding is
unfruitful now what is Paul saying here
Paul is not saying I don't understand
what I'm saying he's saying what I
understand is unfruitful because it's
not benefiting anybody else
my understanding is unfruitful because I
cannot
benefit you with that understanding you
understand nothing I'm saying therefore
what I am saying to you my understanding
is unfruitful
you're not getting what I'm saying so my
understanding is not producing any fruit
come back to the screen
we're almost done yeah we're almost done
my understanding is unfruitful what is
it then I will pray with the spirit and
I will pray with understanding also I
will sing with the spirit and I will
sing with understanding meaning I'm
going to speak and I'm gonna make sure
that what I'm saying others are able to
understand now watch this watch this
this is the text y'all
else then when thou shall blessed with
the spirit how shall he that occupied
the room of the unlearned say Amen at
thy giving of thanks seeing he
understandeth not what you're saying
for verily you give thanks well but the
other is not edified I thank my God I
speak with tongues more than you all yet
in the church I'd rather speak five
words of my understanding that by my
voice I might teach other also then 10
000 words in an unknown tongue meaning a
language that other people don't
understand
what are you doing why are you doing
this
this is why he literally says in First
Corinthians 14 20 Brethren be not
children and understanding how be it and
knowledge be children but in
understanding be men come on y'all let's
not be ridiculous come on y'all let's
not be childish here
use your common sense Corinthians
very next verse in the Lord is written
with men of other tongues and other lips
will I speak unto these people not with
angels of other tongues with men of
other tongues and other lips what I
speak unto these people and yet for all
that they will not hear me say the Lord
wherefore tongues are for a sign not to
them that believe but to them that
believe not
prophesying Seraph not for them that
believe not but for them which believe
why is Paul here saying that tongues are
a gift for them that believe a sign for
them that believe not okay let me tell
you why because then that believe not
were the people who are not Hebrews
were the people who were of other
languages so now when a person of
another language realizes hey wait a
minute
how is it that you're a Hebrew but
you're speaking my language and you say
oh God gave me this gift they're like
man I can verify you never went to
school for this gift never you mean
you actually know how to speak my
language without ever having taken a
class in my language never
okay
who is this God of yours
who is this God of yours that's why it
was a sign for them that believed not
now you tell me if I stand before
somebody and I just start going
over there
before an unbeliever and then say by the
way that's a Heavenly language God gave
me that
what do you think the unbeliever is
going to think about you
you don't have to guess
somebody said Pig Latin
sound like it right you don't have to
guess listen to what Paul himself says
listen to what Paul himself says let's
go back to the screen
it says if therefore the whole church we
come together in one place and shall
speak with tongues
and there come in those that are
unlearned or unbelievers will they not
say you
are somebody said nuts
you are crazy
you are mad
you are out of your mind
whatever this is you are doing
I don't know what it is but I don't want
any part of it
do you see what the devil wants to do
that word from that it literally means
to Rave as a maniac meaning
you're not making any sense
beloved
God is not the god of confusion
he's not the god of Madness he's not the
god of Babel
watch this yeah
this is amazing in the same love chapter
it says this charity never fails but
where there be prophecies they shall
fail where they be tongues they shall
what
come on somebody put that word in the
chat for me where they be tongues they
shall want
cease now come back to come back
come back to the screen with me for a
moment
why would Paul say that tongues would
cease
why would Paul say hey there's coming a
time when tongues are not going to be
needed anymore the gift of tongues is
not going to be needed anymore why would
Paul say that beloved we're living in
that time now
the gospel has gone into many parts of
the world where there's no longer a
problem with people in a certain country
and having never heard the gospel
in in the early church that was not the
case and so God gave the gift now here's
something very interesting people say
well there are two forms of the gift
there is the language part and then
there's the Heavenly language part my
question is why is it that people who
claim to have this gift never are never
able to demonstrate that they can speak
in any other language except the
language that nobody can test
did you all catch what I just said
why do we have no instance in all the
Bible of any disciple
of any individual
speaking in a language that no one
understood but we have examples in the
Bible of people speaking multiple
language languages under the influence
of the Holy Spirit languages that people
could understand if I were to ask you
show me one example in the Bible where
someone is speaking in an unknown tongue
that no one knows
just one verse
I like to call it a root verse a root
text a root text is a text upon which
you can base the rest of your theory on
right so a root text might be the living
know that they shall die but the dead
know not anything and now we're gonna
build on that I'm gonna demonstrate to
you why the living know that they shall
die and the dead no not anything but
where in the Bible can we find any
example of any individual in the old or
new testament speaking a language that
no one understood
it is absent
it is not in the Bible
and yet today many every person that
I've ever known that claims to have the
gift of tongues cannot speak in any
other language unless they went to
school for that language so what is
clearly revealed in the Bible they can't
do it so there's no way to test them but
what isn't revealed oh you know what
would you say I think I said
you see Beloved the devil's trying to
make the church look mad
the devil's trying to make Christianity
look crazy the devil's trying to make
Christianity look like look like y'all
are out of your mind and you really
believe this is God
and he's taking advantage of
well-meaning people
this is not a this is not a stone being
cast to people who currently say hey I
have the gift for a lot of people this
is confirmation that they are connected
with God see I can do this so uh this is
confirmation but if you study the Bible
if you let because let me tell you
something the devil can provide
experiences
just just read the Bible
the devil can appear as an angel of
Light the devil can convince hey this is
miraculous the devil can do the
miraculous
that's why we cannot depend upon signs
like we must depend upon a thus say it
the Lord
and what's interesting is this beloved
if you go into a church where people
speak in tongues and you ask two
different people to interpret the same
the thing that one individual says you
will find that no interpretation matches
come on we're almost done we're almost
done
we're almost there
um let me just I'm gonna
I'm gonna but if prophesied but if all
prophesy and they're coming one that
believeth not all one is on unlearned
he's convincible he's judgable this is
continuing First Corinthians and thus
for the secrets of his heart we're gonna
skip this we're just gonna move on we're
gonna move on listen
listen
here simple version simple understanding
if there be no interpreter let the
individual keep silent in the church and
let him speak to himself and to God you
don't see this
you don't say this
it's almost as if this verse has been
removed from from many people's Bibles
now if you're remaining silent
with this particular tongue what sense
does it make to even speak it
did y'all catch what I just said the
text says if there be no interpreter
keep silent and speak
to yourself
you want to pray to God in French go
ahead and pray to God in French you want
to pray to God in Spanish go ahead and
pray to God in Spanish
but if you're praying in Spanish in a
church that is that is English or
praying
in English that a church is in Spanish
just to show off that you can pray in
English or pray in Spanish
come on y'all don't do not be
children and understanding be chosen and
knowledge but don't be children and
understanding
come on a few more verses we're going to
wrap this up I promise you uh um go back
to the screen uh uh the spirit of
prophets are substance of the prophets
for God is not the author of confusion
but of Peace in all the churches of the
Saints the devil seeks to bring in
confusion that will stop the building up
of the church stop the building up of
the city of God and this is one of the
ways in which he seeks to do it Babylon
confusion
Revelation 14 8 says and there followed
another Angel saying Babylon has fallen
has fallen that great City because she
made all nations drink of the wine of
the wrath of her fornication you
understand that Babylon is trying to
exalt herself to heaven and Babylon
which represents a a a system of
churches that are teaching error beloved
one of the most dominant eras is the era
of Babel in the name of Jesus because it
makes the church look crazy to
unbelievers and this is what the devil
is doing so let me break this down very
quickly
why the gift of tongues
why the gift of tongues the Bible says
again they're appeared unto them cloven
tongues like as a fire and it's sat upon
each one of them why the gift of tongues
first of all Isaiah 6 6 says this then
through one of the seraphims unto me
having a live call in his hand which he
had taken with the tongs from off the
Altar and he laid it upon my mouth and
said Lo this has touched thy lips and
thine iniquity is taken away and thy sin
is purged why the gift of tongues
because God was demonstrating that
through the sacrifice of his son he had
purged his people and had purged their
lips so that they could now go out and
preach the gospel with power
that's why the the gift came in the
symbol of tongues
why tongues of fire because God was
signifying that that you're you that I
am purifying you to go and preach the
gospel why clothing come back Matthew
chapter 16 Mark 16 verse 15.
he said unto them go into all the world
and preach the gospel to Every Creature
you see a cloven tongue is divided
meaning there are Parts God is saying
I'm giving you languages that is going
to be able to reach Every Nation Kindred
tongue and people so that the gospel can
reach into all the world and why fire
the Bible says in Jeremiah 2019 20 verse
9 then I said I will not make mention of
his name nor speak anymore in his name
but his word was in my heart as a
burning fire shut up in my bones and I
was weary with forbearing and I could
not stay Beloved the gift of tongues is
simply designed it is simply designed
it is simply designed to show that the
gift of tongs was given to his people to
spread the word with fire with passion
to take it into all the world and when
the time when the time began to come
that the gospel was going into all the
world the gift of tongues as we
understand it in the Bible was no longer
necessary
but I will show you this this is our
closing text
you see beloved everybody is supposed to
have a tongue of Fire
everybody will have a tongue of Fire
you can either have the fire of the
spirit on your tongue not meaning
necessarily that you're speaking some
other language but your tongue is set on
fire because it's on fire for God
or you can have this fire
James chapter 3 verse 5.
where the Bible says even so the tongue
is a little member and boasts it's great
things behold how great a matter a
little fire Kindles
and the tongue is a fire a world of
iniquity so is the tongue among our
members that it defileth the whole body
and set it on fire the course of Nature
and it is set on fire of Hell listen to
me
we're wrapping this up
you can either your tongue can either be
on fire for God or it can be on fire for
the devil
I need you to understand this listen to
me and I see a coming in the chat actors
box let me say this if you're in a place
where God feels it necessary to give you
the gift of tongue so you can reach a
people that don't understand you he will
give you that gift that's a legitimate
use and understanding of the gift of
tongues
but what we see happening today
beloved you cannot find it in the word
of God
you can find it if you misapply a
certain text but you cannot find any
example of any such thing happening
among any of the disciples among any of
the churches ever
I pray today
that this message would have touched
someone who needs to hear and understand
this
God is not the author of confusion
it is so interesting if you were to go
into the commentaries
free the the commentaries before the
1800s
before the late 1800s to look at how
commentators almost unanimously uh
explained First Corinthians chapter 14.
you will see that they were almost all
unanimous with you know languages
languages languages languages it was not
until the modern movement
that people started taking this to mean
some unknown language which no one
understands including the speaker him or
herself
beloved we need to have the tongues of
fire and that means we need to have
tongues that are set on fire for God
that's the tongue that we need now
why because God has a mission for us
to finish building the city
to finish building that to damage to
show the entire world this is the way
to get to heaven
we have a work to do
we got stones to collect and we need the
mortar of the spirit to bring it all
together
you want to be a part of that work
you need to be rightly equipped with the
gifts beloved not false gifts not
counterfeit gifts you need to be rightly
equipped with the word of God with the
spirit of Christ and with the truth
I pray this message touch you today if
that's you please put a one in the chat
if it's challenge you put a one in the
chat if you feel like Matt I need to
study more I need to understand more put
that one in the chat I'm going to ask
Rick our our uh I'm gonna ask our team
to put up our Bible workers contact
information if you're saying today okay
I need to study this out and I need to
really understand I want to study with
someone and I really want to get to the
to the bottom of what truth is please
there is our Bible workers contact
information in in the um uh on the
screen
may God bless you as you continue your
search for truth and I invite you to
pray with me Heavenly Father
please
I pray that all who hear this message
who who are even now caught up in this
in this
understanding of what tongues is
that after hearing this message
they might get a clearer picture of why
you gave this gift and what the true
gift of tongues is
versus what is commonly understood to be
the gift of tongues today
Lord speak to your people bless us
forgive us of our sins forgive us of our
ignorance Lord and may we be drawn
closer to you and ultimately be drawn
into Heavenly places through the Tower
and the city you have prepared for us in
Jesus name we pray amen and amen I want
to invite all of you watching too if you
would like to join us on altar live to
join our after
um uh after discussion our Afterglow uh
there is a link in the chat and uh may
God bless you and and continue to draw
you closer to him is our prayer amen and
amen
thank you for joining us today if this
is your first time worshiping with us
please check out our website at
livingmanna.church we are not just here
for Sabbath service we have weekly
programming too that covers mental
health physical health weekly prayer
service financial help and proving the
existence of God it is our desire that
our programming will continue to bless
you please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the Gospel of Jesus Christ
[Music]
thank you